A Guide to the William Trager papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA202
Rockefeller Archive Center
William Trager papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1933-1972
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Trager, William
FA202
6.84 Cubic Feet 18 boxes.
18 boxes.
Biographical/Historical note
William Trager (1910-) was the head of a parasitology laboratory at the Rockefeller University and a leading authority on parasitic protozoa.
Born in Newark, NJ, Trager earned his B.S. at Rutgers University in 1930 By 1933, he had completed his M.A. and Ph. D. at Harvard University. Trager became a member of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research in 1935. Until then, he was a fellow at the Institute. Trager became an associate professor at the RIMR in 1950 and was appointed professor of biology in 1964.
Dr. Trager and an associate, Dr. James B. Jensen, conducted research on cultivating uncontaminated mosquito cultures. They were one of the first to cultivate Palsmodium falciparum, with hopes of making an effective vaccine against malaria in humans.
Within Trager's laboratory, the electron microscope was first used for parasitology. This had allowed them to understand more of the parasites' DNA which has promoted the culture method for other organisms, as well.
Scope and Contents note
Consists of laboratory notebooks and their enclosures.
Arrangement note
Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 T677
Conditions Governing Access note
Access to this collection is restricted pending permission from Rockefeller University.
Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Life sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Medical technology; Malaria vaccine; Medical research; Parasitology; Malaria; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Animal Records Straining Passages, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Apos. Cil. Book I, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Apos. Cil. Book I, Enclosures, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Apos. Cil. Book II, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Apos. Cil. Book III, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Apos. Cil. Book IV, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Apos. Cil. Book IV, Enclosures, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Antabrines - Animal Records, Miscellaneous Penicillin, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Antabrines - Antabrines NH4, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Antabrines - Antabrine Data, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Antabrines - Summary Of Data Relapses, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Antabrines - 4th General Hospital, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Antabrines - Antibrine Levels, 4th General Hospital, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Babesia, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Babesia Enclosures, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Biotin - Biotin I, Notes On Malaria And Other Matters, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Biotin - Biotin I, Notes On Malaria And Other Matters Enclosures, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Biotin - Biotin II, Notes, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Biotin - Biotin III, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Biotin - Biotin IV, Work At Base "F", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Biotin - Biotin V, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Biotin - Biotin V, Enclosures, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Biotin - Biotin VI, Work At 19th Med. Gen. Lab APO 565, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Biotin - Biotin VII, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays I, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays II, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays III, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays III, Enclosures, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays IV, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays IV, Enclosures, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays V, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays VI, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays VII, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays VIII, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays IX, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays X, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XI, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XII, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XII, Enclosures, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XIII, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XIV, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XIV, Enclosures (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XV, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XVI, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XVI, Enclosures, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XVII, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Biotin - Biotin Assays XVTII, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Book 9, 1933 (?) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Book 10, Enclosure, 1933 (?) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. I, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. II, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. III, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. IV, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. V, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. VI, 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Chem. Studies - C.S. VII, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. I, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. II, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. III, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. IV, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. V, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. VI, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. VII, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. VIII, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. IX, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. IX, Enclosures, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. X, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XI, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XII, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XIII, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XIV, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XV, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XVI, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XVII, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XVIII, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XIX, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XX, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XXI, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XXII, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XXIII, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XXIII, Enclosure, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XXIV, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Chicken Malaria - CM. XXV, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Chicken Tumors - C.T. I, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Chicken Tumors - C.T. I, Enclosures, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Chicken Tumors - C.T. II, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Chicken Tumors - C.T. II, Enclosures, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Chicken Tumors - C.T. III, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Chicken Tumors - C.T. IV, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Cultivation - CNS I, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Cultivation - CNS II, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Cultivation - CNS III, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Cultivation - CNS IV, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Cultivation - CNS V, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Cultivation - CNS VI, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Cultivation - CNS VII, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Cultivation - CNS VIII, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Cultivation - CNS IX, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Cultivation - CNS X, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- E.E. Virus I, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- E.E. Virus II, 1937-1938 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- E.E. Virus II, Enclosures, 1937-1938 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Hamster Diet, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
- ITC I, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- ITC II, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- ITC III, 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- ITC IV, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- ITC IV, Enclosures, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- ITC V, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- ITC V, Enclosure, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- ITC VI, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- ITC VII, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- ITC VII, Enclosures, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- ITC VIII, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- ITC IX, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- ITC IX, Enclosures, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- ITC X, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- ITC XI, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- ITC XII, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- ITC XIII, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- ITC XIV, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- ITC XIV Enclosures, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- ITC XV, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- ITC XVI, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- ITC XVII, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Malaria - Malaria Comm. Notes I, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Malaria - Malaria Comm. Notes I, Enclosures, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Malaria - Malaria Comm. Notes II, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Malaria - Malaria Comm. Notes II, Enclosures, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Malaria - Malaria Comm. Notes III, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Mosquito Growth I, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Mosquito Growth II, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Mosquito Growth III, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Mosquito Growth III, Enclosures, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Mosquito Growth IV, 1935-1936 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Mosquito Growth V, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Mosquito Growth V, Enclosures, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Mosquito Growth VI, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Mosquito Growth VII, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Mosquito Growth VIII, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Mosquito Growth IX, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Mosquito Growth X, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Mosquito Growth XI, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Mosquito Growth XII, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Mosquito Growth XIII, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Mosquito Growth XIV, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Mosquito Growth XV, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Mosquito Growth XVI, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Mosquito Growth XVII, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Mosquito Growth XVIII, 1937-1938 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Mosquito Growth XIX, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Mosquito Growth XX, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Mosquito Growth XXI, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Mosquito Growth XXII, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Mosquito Growth XXIII, 1939-1941 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Pebrine I, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Pebrine I Enclosures, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Pebrine II, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Pebrine III, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Protozoa - The Cell, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Protozoa - The Cell Enclosures, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Resistance (Passive Transfer) I, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Resistance (Passive Transfer) II, 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Resistance (Passive Transfer) II, Enclosures, 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Resistance (Passive Transfer) III, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Resistance (Passive Transfer) III, Enclosures, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Special Notes - Austrial Camp Hospital Visit, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Special Notes I - Malaria Parasite In Vitro, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Special Notes II - Malaria Parasite In Vitro, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Special Notes III - Malaria Parasite In Vitro, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Special Notes IV - Malaria Parasite In Vitro, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Special Notes V - Malaria Parasite In Vitro, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Special Notes VI - Malaria Parasite In Vitro, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Special Notes VII - Azaserine, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Special Notes VII - Azaserine, Enclosure, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Special Notes VIII - Azaserine, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Special Notes VIII - Azaserine, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Special Notes IX, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Special Notes X, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Special Notes XI, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Special Notes XII, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Special Notes XIII, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Special Notes XIII, Enclosure, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
- S.W.D. I, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- S.W.D. I, Enclosures, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- S.W.D. II, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Therapy, 1942-1943 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Therapy, Enclosures, 1942-1943 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Ticks I, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Ticks I, Enclosures, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Ticks II, 1937-1938 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Ticks II, Enclosures, 1937-1938 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Ticks III, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Ticks III, Enclosures, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Ticks IV, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Ticks V, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Ticks VI, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Ticks VII, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Ticks VII, Enclosures, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Vaughani - Hex Amerium Group (With Huff), 1942 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Woods Hole Marine Biological Laboratory, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Woods Hole Marine Biological Laboratory Enclosures, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 14)